Guide to the Thomas Clap, President of Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Thomas Clap, president of Yale College, records
1720-1765
RU 130
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.08
(2 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, memoirs, notes, observations, and other writings of Thomas Clap concerning Yale College.
Yale College (1718-1887). President's Office
Clap, Thomas, 1703-1767
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas Clap served as president of Yale College from 1740 to 1766.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoirs, notes, observations, and other writings of Thomas Clap concerning Yale College.
Arrangement
The records are arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; College presidents; Educators; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Administration; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Presidents; Yale College (1718-1887). President's Office
- Records of Thomas Clap, Accession 1935-A-010
  - Notes of Sermons and other colleges exercises during his undergraduate course, 1720 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions and Indentures, 1739, 1743, 1747 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - College Memoirs, 1743 (?) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Writings, 1746-1765 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Investigation of the alleged poisoning of college students in Commons, 1764 (Box 2)
  - Annals of Yale College, 1747 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Enquiry into the Foundation of Moral Virtue and Obligation", 1748 (?) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Present State of the Colony of Connecticut Considered", 1754 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Account of the Cost of the New College, 1748-1752 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sundry accounts and memoranda, 1749-1754 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes of sermon, Thanksgiving, 1754 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Admissions of Students..., 1757-1766 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter on the Right of Appeal of Students in College, 1764 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Some observations relating to the Government of Yale College [with 2 typescripts], 1764 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annals of Yale College, 1765 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Memoirs of some remarkable occurences of divine providence..., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Scope and Contents
    Manuscript recollections of Thomas Clap, including an essay titled "Meditations on the Death of My Wife, August 9, 1736."
  - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)